♪ In the not
too distant future ♪
♪ Way down in Deep 13 ♪
♪ Doctor Forrester
and TV's Frank ♪
♪ Were hatching
an evil scheme ♪
♪ They hired a temp
by the name of Mike ♪
♪ Just a regular Joe
they didn't like ♪
♪ Their experiment needed
a good test case ♪
♪ So they conked him
on the noggin' ♪
♪ And they shot him into space ♪
[Mike] Get me down!
♪ We'll send him
cheesy movies ♪
-♪ The worst we can find ♪
-♪ la la la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
-♪ and we'll monitor his mind ♪
-♪ la la la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Mike can't control ♪
♪ where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ la la la ♪
♪ He'll try to keep his sanity ♪
♪ with the help
of his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
-♪ Cambot ♪
- Cover yourself!
-♪ Gypsy ♪
- I'm not ready!
-♪ Tom Servo ♪
- Hello there!
-♪ Crow ♪
- That's one "o"!
♪ If you're wondering
how he eats and breathes ♪
-♪ and other science facts ♪
-♪ la la la ♪
♪ Just repeat to yourself
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For
Mystery Science Theater 3000 ♪
[doors closing]
Hi there! Welcome to
the Satellite of Love .
Hey, this here
is my science project.
Servo! Let me out!
I-- I think I'm having
some sort of reaction to Ethel.
That's ether, Crow.
Yes, this here is the crown
jewel of my insect collection.
-Hodusrobotus horriblus.
-Servo. Servo, I mean it!
Note the strong
and deadly mandibles.
Hey, watch this.
-[Tom makes noises]
-[Crow screams]
[Tom laughs]
Stay tuned,
after a commercial break,
we'll tear his wings off
and burn him
with a magnifying glass.
[Tom makes noises]
I'll get the pliers.
Attica! Attica! Attica!
Attica!
[theme music playing]
[Tom] I chase the...
-How do I look?
-[Tom] Oh, great!
-Terrific as a matter of fact.
-You're not just saying that,
are ya? Cause I-- I-- I--
I feel kinda bloated.
That's just the formaldehyde,
trust me,
-you're a fine specimen.
-Servo. My God.
-I don't believe this.
-Well, it's a...
A black-banded Holomolina.
Do you have any idea
how rare those are?
[Tom] Oh yeah.
They're kinda rare--
Uh, I don't mean
to interrupt but uh,
I believe the Mads are calling.
-Oh, yeah.
-Sure. Whatever.
Really though, I'm impressed.
I mean, where in this kind of
an area did you find one
of these.
Well, our bed and breakfast
seems to be taking off.
As you can see, the bed
is completely filled.
Ted. Barb.
Rise and shine!
Time to get up now. C'mon.
Get up. Get up. C'mon.
C'mon. C'mon.
-[slap]
-[shouting]
Well, well, well.
Good morning and welcome to
Auntie McFrank's
Tangleberry Inn.
Auntie McFrank, you gave me
quite a bit of start there.
Oh, what a nice,
cheery wake-up call.
I trust you'll be joining us
for breakfast.
-Oh, mais oui .
-Yes, according to the brochure,
the Tangleberry breakfasts
are to die for.
Well put.
[chuckles]
Auntie McFrank, why don't
you fetch one
of your scrumptious breakfasts
for Barb and Ted?
Oh, good.
Now, what are we having?
Oh, don't ask honey,
I wanna be surprised.
Right, sweets.
[chuckling]
-Now, Clay,
-Huh?
you and Auntie McFrank,
do you umm,
are you...
Partners?
Yes, we're...
-Ah! Here it is.
-Ah!
Uh, now, um, what exactly do
we have...
-Lo Mein.
-Oh, Lo Mein.
I'll heat it up for you,
if you like.
Some like it warm,
-you know.
-No, no. Please don't bother.
Yeah. You know what, I tell you,
we're actually more interested
in maybe taking a look around,
getting to know the area.
Uh, soaking in a little
of the local color.
Ah, the local color.
Yes. We understand
that you have a llama.
Ah, the llama.
Yeah. We'd love
to pet the llama.
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Mike, did you guys put
on the stuff I sent up to you?
It's time for the local color.
Suppose you folks want to touch
the llama, huh?
That's right, huh?
You wanna touch this old llama?
Oh, you just go right ahead.
You can touch the ol' llama
all you want.
You can touch
the ol' llama all night
till hell freezes over.
[chuckles]
Not me, though. Uh- huh.
No sirree, Bob.
I wouldn't touch
that old thing.
llama hasn't been feeling
so good.
Whew. Smells funny too.
Whoa.
Smells really
kind of rank, you know?
But you can touch it
if you want.
Ain't no law says you can't.
Ain't that right, Mikey?
Ain't there no laws that says
folks can't touch
the smelly ol' llama
if they want, huh, Mikey, huh?
Huh?
You people bring matches
for Mikey?
You shut up, Mikey,
you shut up!
You folks don't give no matches
to Mikey, you hear me?
You hear me? I don't care
what Mikey say or Mikey do.
Don't give him no matches!
I don't care
if Mikey come crawling
in through your window.
Start making a big old mess!
Don't you give no matches
to Mikey!
Don't you give
no matches--
-Shut up, Mikey!
-[Crow squawking]
-Shut up, llama!
-No!
-Just shut up, under--
Don't give him matches!
No matches to Mikey!
Shut up, Mikey!
[Auntie McFrank]
Ted! Barb!
Aren't you going to sign
the guest book?
Please, I want you
to write something cute
and nice and enchanting,
please I have to--
You'll pay for this, Nelson.
I was going to let
you watch Holiday Inn .
But, not anymore. No! No!
Instead, you'll visit
with the very inhospitable
Amazing Transparent Man .
Put that in your llama
and smell it.
You give me this pillow,
it doesn't need fluffing!
[groan]
[laughing]
[Crow] You can stop
that now, Mikey.
Oh, we got movie sign!
[doors opening]
[laughing]
[Crow] Union Pacific makes
the best movies.
[Tom] Shh, you guys.
This is my story. My story's on.
[Mike] Is that a lung?
[music playing]
[Tom] Ah, the best cast
that Union Pacific
has to offer.
[Crow]
If there's a reverend in it,
-you know it's gotta be good.
-[Tom] Amen.
[Mike] Quite a coup getting
Francois Poulenc
to do the music.
[Tom] Herman Boxer and Joseph
Ansen were the Babaloo Mandel
and Lowell Ganz of their time.
[Crow] Whoo,
Whiter Shade of Pale .
[Tom] Go in peace to love
and serve Union Pacific.
[Mike] So, we have 70 days
in each year?
-[Tom] Pretty much.
-[Crow] We're gonna have to go
a long way
to get back to train safety.
[Tom] Our car is kind of
a downer tonight.
[Mike] It's up
with brakemen.
[Crow] Castrati's greatest hits.
[Tom] What, let's visit
Sister Bertrille.
[reverend] It is written
in the Old Testament,
to each of us,
this allotment of years,
three score and ten.
[Crow] I sure tore
through mine.
[reverend] And in these years,
there is the time of man.
[Tom] Yeah, shame
he died, huh?
[reverend] Time to fulfill
his destiny.
To work together
with his fellow man
in the wonderfully,
complex pattern
of everyday life.
[Crow] Ah, they really captured
the complexity.
[reverend] A time to be born,
-[Tom] Oh yum.
-[reverend] A time to grow.
[reverend] To become aware
of the loveliness
of all things living.
[Tom] Sure, this beats
having friends.
[reverend] In the call
of youth to youth,
to learn the happiest lesson
of all...
[Crow] Dishes.
...that the fullness of life
can only be tasted
when our happiness
is shared with others.
[Tom laughing]
[Tom] Alright. Go dad!
[reverend] Later, a time
of maturity,
-to reflect, to relax,
-[Tom] It all sucked.
-[reverend] ...to enjoy.
-[Crow] I regret everything.
[reverend] Yes, this is the
heritage to which we are born.
The blessings to which we may
all look forward.
[Tom] Really going through
the funerals.
[reverend] Yet,
here in my parish,
there are some
who can only look back.
[Crow] I hate them.
[reverend] They are the victims,
unable to reap
the full enjoyment
of the days of their years.
[Mike] Chief Justice,
Earl Warren.
[reverend] They are the victims
of themselves.
[Tom] I hate themselves.
[reverend] My church
is in a railroad town,
not far from a big freight
terminal and repair shop.
-[Mike] All mine.
-[reverend] In my congregation
are railroad people
in every capacity.
[Mike] Boy, he thinks loud.
[reverend] And not one
who isn't safety conscious.
[Tom] Not one who isn't drunk.
[reverend] Accident-haters
all of us.
Hating the waste, the pain,
the needlessness.
[Crow]
The filth that is humanity.
[reverend] Yet, try as we may,
do what we will,
-there comes a time,
-[Tom] I'm bigger than Jesus.
[siren blaring]
[Mike] Oh, no. The reverend
just killed again.
[Crow]
Ironically, the ambulance driver
hit four people
on the way there.
[Servo sobbing]
[reverend] A fellow worker
hurt.
[Mike] Get out of town,
accident lover!
[reverend] People
never get hardened
to a sight like this.
[Crow]
I had an accident, too.
[reverend] But, it isn't only
what happens
-to the man in the ambulance.
-[Crow] No?
[reverend]
There's another story
-behind most accidents.
-[Tom] Communism.
[reverend] The story,
of what happens to the others.
[Mike] The doctor's wife
had died, he paused to smell--
[reverend] You might say,
I've got sort of an inside track
when it comes
to knowing the inside story
behind an accident.
It strikes me that the ones
who are hurt most
by the carelessness
that causes accidents
are the ones
who weren't even there.
[Crow]
I didn't hate accidents enough.
[Tom] Shame.
I often stopped by here
for a cup of coffee.
[Mike]
That's really interesting.
[reverend] Whenever I do,
I'm reminded
of the things that happened
to the people
who weren't even there.
-Oh, sure-- huh?
-[Mike chuckling]
[reverend] I re-read the story
in the sad eyes
of the girl who serves me.
[Tom]
And it really pisses me off.
[Crow] Yes, I'm ruddy.
-This is Helen.
-[Tom] Hi, Helen.
[reverend] Although,
she has never been
-in an accident, Helen is,
-[Tom] She acts like she has.
nevertheless,
an accident victim.
[Mike]
Now can I get my pancakes?
[reverend] Her eyes were not
always sorrowful.
Once they were bright
and shiny.
[Crow] Her coat glossy.
[reverend] Yes, I remember,
how those eyes used to glow
whenever Helen
thought about Joe.
-Joe Tendler was--
-[Tom] It's a belt sander!
-[Servo screaming]
-[reverend] In those days,
Joe was about as average
a young fellow
-as you'd be likely to meet.
-[Mike] He sounds great.
[reverend] Young, easygoing,
good company.
[Crow] Prone to violence.
[reverend] He hadn't a complaint
in the world.
Well, maybe one complaint.
He was getting a little tired
of being a bachelor.
Eating on the run,
cleaning up your own place,
-[Servo laughing]
-if you got around to it.
But all that was due
for a change pretty soon.
[Tom] He'd chosen
his new look.
[reverend] Yes,
Joe was a pretty lucky guy.
Good job
as road electrical foreman,
wonderful girl
who wanted nothing
in the world more than
to be Mrs. Joe.
-[Tom] So his name is Joe Joe?
-[Mike] I guess so.
[reverend] On his way to the job
that morning,
Joe had to stop by
to see Helen.
There was something
he'd forgotten to
give her last night.
A taste of the spoiler.
[Tom] I spilled my coffee,
it's hot!
"In front of all these people,
behave!"
[Mike makes noises]
But of course, Joe was behaving.
The was any lucky, happy,
young fellow
about to be married
would behave.
It was only natural.
Joe had to take off in an hurry
to reach that job on time.
He had a lot more women to kiss
on his route that morning.
[reverend] And Helen,
well, she was on the job,
and her face
had that glad look,
I'll always remember.
[Tom] My man is average.
[reverend]
It made people feel good
just watching her feeling good.
as she went
through the motions,
[Tom]
I'm watching you feel good.
[reverend] Though she was quick
and sure and competent
in everything she did,
-She spit in the eggs.
-[reverend] She was really
a million miles away
from that little restaurant.
[Tom] Mr. and Mrs. Joe Toast.
[reverend] A million miles away.
-In a dream world, all her own,
-[Tom] Come over to this side.
[Crow] Obey the toaster!
[reverend]
That dream world had everything,
a church, complete
with ministers,
-saying the proper words.
-[Tom] You are getting sleepy.
[reverend] I was flattered
to be a part of Helen's dream.
-[Tom] Ew.
-[Crow] Ew.
[reverend]
There was a ring in it,
and of course,
-a beautiful dress and veil.
-[Tom] For Joe.
[reverend]
And the handsome groom.
[Mike] And me, of course.
[chuckling]
[reverend] And when the ceremony
was over,
there was the first
of many, many kisses.
[Crow] In my version,
things went a lot further.
[reverend] Yes, this was Helen's
very own dream.
And she was going to make
it worth dreaming.
[Tom] Well, I gotta get back
to my shift, honey.
[reverend] She wasn't skimping
on anything.
[Mike]
She dreamed of tract housing.
[reverend]
There was that perfectly,
scrumptious model house
she'd been wanting
for all these years.
-[Crow] Squalor contemporary.
-[reverend] There it was,
exactly as she'd imagined.
And here they were,
what was the sense in waiting.
[Tom]
Plan Five from Outer Space .
[reverend]
The fastest sale on record.
And while she was dreaming,
she'd furnished that house
that very afternoon.
So Joe could read
his evening paper
on that pretty couch
that very night.
-[Mike] Where's my damn dinner?
-[reverend] Where she could take
that paper away
and cuddle close.
[Tom] Ooh.
[reverend] She'd dreamed
of everything
any dreamy young girl
had ever dreamed before.
[Tom] They're in Hell!
[reverend] Of crackling fires,
of dimmed lights,
of love.
[Crow] They should've
had a train scene here.
[reverend]
And even in her dreams,
Helen missed Joe
when he was gone.
[Mike]
That was so incredibly average.
[reverend]
She was a clever dreamer,
[baby cooing]
so she arranged for little Joe
to be there to keep her
from getting lonesome
when daddy was away.
[Crow] Speaking of accidents.
[reverend]
Beginning of a new life,
but the end of a dream.
[Tom] Okay. Diaper
the toast and butter the baby.
[Servo buzzing]
[reverend] But on the job late
in the afternoon of that day,
the real-life Joe
was in a real live hurry.
He hadn't seen his Helen
since early that morning.
[Tom singing]
♪ Wichita lineman ♪
[reverend] "C'mon, you guys.
Get a move on.
Let's get out of here."
[Crow]
He might've been heard to say.
[reverend]
To the impatient Joe,
the men seemed almost
purposely stalling
as they stowed their gear.
[Tom] Joe smelled conspiracy
in everything.
[reverend] And now, the wheels
of fate were set in motion.
Call them the wheels of fate,
or the wheels of chance,
-[Tom] Or call them Ernie.
-[reverend] but consider,
the man of the wheel
was in the driver's seat.
[Tom]
Any case it involved a wheel.
[reverend] It was Joe
who was calling
the turn of the wheel.
[Mike]
Joe is the king of the world.
[reverend]
They went through a stop sign,
Better take it easy, Joe.
[Crow]
Get out of my head, reverend!
[music playing]
[Tom] Joe's thirst for danger
seems quite reasonable.
[reverend] The others,
they were along for the ride,
whether they liked it or not.
Liked it? They hated it.
-[Tom] A flag on the moon.
-[reverend] What could they do?
They were trapped.
Yes, Joe had a lady,
and he just couldn't get
there fast enough.
[Tom] For those two scoops
of raisins,
[tires squealing]
[Tom] Oh, not again, Joe!
[Crow] That's your standard
crash Foley.
[reverend]
Now, it was payoff time.
One, still able to move.
Two, still able to move.
They had escaped the trap.
[Tom]
It was an average accident.
[reverend] Their threescore
and ten were still before them.
[Mike] Give or take a score.
[reverend]
But the trap had sprung on Joe.
-[Crow] Serve 'ya right.
-[reverend] Yes.
Now, it was payoff time.
[Tom]
Such are the wages of sex.
[reverend]
Easy going Joe Tendler,
[Mike]
Was trapped in his own juicer.
Joe became
an avant-garde composer.
[reverend] After a year
in that neck brace,
Joe wasn't quite
such good company
as he used to be.
But the Word said,
for better or for worse,
in sickness or in health,
[Tom]
Do you take this bionic man?
[reverend]
Sure, Jo tried to call it off,
but a girl
like Helen doesn't run out.
There was quite a difference
between Helen's dream
and the reality,
there'd be quite a difference
between living
with the dream Joe
and the real one.
[Crow] Their honeymoon at Six
Flags is going to be real fun.
-[Tom] Hey, Joe.
-[Servo choking and yelling]
[reverend]
It needn't have happened at all.
[Tom] You could've married me.
[Mike] Look at this button I
found in the collection plate.
[theme music playing]
[reverend] There are many days
in the years left for Joe,
[Mike] Too many.
[reverend] For George Price,
there are fewer.
[Tom] Hey, you dead yet?
[reverend] And the days
George does have left,
are embittered days.
-[Crow scoffing]
-[reverend] Flavorless.
Futile.
[Crow] Get off my land,
you pious son of a--
[reverend] To George, the sound
of that approaching car
as it nears the house
across the street,
prods back into his memory,
a scene he has fought to erase,
[Mike] But then so does
every other sound.
[reverend]
The scene he cannot forget.
[Tom] He's having a great day.
[reverend] This is Lenny Bellows
the boy across the street.
The boy who once
was like a son to George.
Just across the street.
Where everyday, George can't
possibly help seeing him.
[Crow] Better go buy
some salt pellets.
[reverend] Everyday,
George remembers.
[Mike] When he was good friends
with Dean Rusk.
[reverend] George remembers
how it was in the happy days,
with the Price
and Bellows families.
[Tom] Eating sandwiches.
[reverend] Fred Bellows,
Lenny's father, and George,
good neighbors,
good friends.
[Tom] And Michelob.
[reverend] They'd spend hours
figuring the fun they'd have
-on their retirement pay.
-[all cheering]
The trips they'd take together.
The wonderful places
they'd see.
It would be soon now.
[Crow]
Let's go on a Hawaiian sex tour.
[reverend]
Their wives had waited patiently
through all the long years
of railroad service.
-[Tom] Tony Dow!
-[reverend] Lenny would go
to college. It was all planned.
There wasn't a cloud
in the bright, blue sky
-of their future.
-[Mike] Then, I showed up.
[Servo chuckling]
[reverend] Forty-two years
of good, honest work.
George was proud of those years.
-[Tom] George.
-Proud of the strength.
and stamina
that had kept him going.
But today, somehow,
he didn't feel so good.
And when it was time
to go back to work,
George wondered whether he
was going to be able to make it.
[Crow] George, you're hilarious.
[reverend]
Funny, these last few weeks
he hadn't been
quite up to snuff.
[Tom] Diarrhea is like a stone.
[reverend] Nobody noticed,
he hadn't mentioned it,
-probably just indigestion.
-[Mike] Hey,
have a massive coronary
on your own time.
[reverend] He'll be alright.
If he could only hold out
until retirement time.
[Crow] It's at
5 o'clock today.
[reverend]
But now he had a job to do.
And nobody
was going to say
George Price gave up
on the job.
[Tom] George Price gave up
on the job. There, I said it.
[reverend]
And so, as Fred Bellows
climbed up to go back
to his job,
George went back to his.
[Mike]
Robust and cheerful as ever.
[reverend]
A small voice whispered,
"Report sick. Get a relief man.
-Don't be a fool, George".
-[Crow] Kill your parents.
[reverend]
But George had a job to do,
and he was going to stick to it.
[Mike] Boo Radley waved him on.
[reverend] So, there was George
and Fred,
and Bill said,
"C'mon, easy."
[Crow]
They called him the "derailer".
[Mike] Well,
what's with Georgey Worgey?
[music playing]
[Tom] Shouldn't have thought
of Mamie Eisenhower.
[music playing]
[Tom] Uh, George,
if this is one of your pranks...
[Servo chuckling]
[Mike] Oh, this is terrible.
He died minutes
before his time.
[Tom] Good one, George.
[reverend] George tried to go
to Fred Bellows funeral...
[Crow] But Baywatch was on.
[reverend]
...but the doctor said no.
You don't walk around two days
after a heart attack.
[Mike] Why couldn't he have
killed the guy two doors down?
[reverend] But it couldn't keep
him away from the window.
He watched Grace and Lenny,
-[Tom] And Squiggy.
-[reverend] Lenny,
who wouldn't
be going to college this fall...
-Because he's dumb.
-[reverend] ...or any fall.
[Tom] Can you bring me back
a program?
[reverend]
Grace, who faced a future
of grief and loneliness,
[Tom] Boring.
[Crow]
There. My problem went away.
[Mike] Alright. Let's get
this guy planted.
[Crow] They'll circle George's
house a few times,
then go on to the cemetery.
[reverend]
That was over three years ago.
[Tom] George hasn't moved.
[reverend] George still can't
get around very well.
Lenny Bellows still lives
across the street.
And though he has long
since forgiven George,
yet his simplest actions
have become, to George,
signs of rejection and hatred.
[Mike] You know,
staring off into space
hasn't been as exciting
as I thought it would be.
[reverend] There George Price
was doomed to stay,
across a little street,
a thousand miles wide.
[Crow] Now, let's get
to the dismemberment.
[reverend] As I said before,
most of my congregation
are railroad people.
I know the road does everything
in its power
to prevent accidents.
To see that equipment
and working procedures
in the shops are as safe
as it's possible to make them.
And by constant reminders
to keep the men aware
of the life
and death importance
of observing safety rules.
[Tom]
See our elaborate safety system?
[Servo chuckling]
[reverend] Yet, still they come.
-[Mike] This is Needle Park.
-[reverend] The ones who forget
even for the barest fraction
of a second,
that with safety,
there are no second chances.
[Crow]
Oh, well. Who needs fingers?
[reverend] Not all trips
to the hospital, though,
-are necessarily disastrous.
-[Tom] Just mine.
[reverend]
For example, there was the trip
Charlie O'Neil made
with his wife.
That was about
the happiest trip
Charlie ever took.
He and Sue had been
looking forward to it for years.
Waiting. Hoping.
-[Crow] For a pap smear?
-[reverend] Finally it happened.
There'd be a new little O'Neil
along any minute now.
Charlie was so happy
he forgot everything else.
-[Servo chuckling]
-Well, almost everything.
[Mike] He almost forgot
his ventriloquial figure.
[Servo laughing]
[reverend] He didn't quite
believe them a little later
when they told him
it might take a while
and he might as well go back
to work.
[Tom] This has nothing
to do with you. Go on.
[music playing]
[reverend] On the way
to the shop,
-he remembered something.
-[Crow] He had to go kiss Helen.
[reverend]
It was just about the last thing
he did remember that day,
Cigars.
[Mike] He was going
to Ernie Kovacs' house.
[reverend] They weren't
going to catch Charlie off-base
when the big news came.
[Crow] Charlie was close now.
You could smell him.
[reverend] He hoped it wouldn't
be too long
-before he could break them out.
-[Tom] So he disrobed.
[reverend]
There was a phone call coming,
he told the Foreman, a big one.
Please get it to him fast
when it came.
[Crow] Ah, get back to work.
[reverend] Charlie did remember
one more thing that day.
To take proper care
getting Bill's attention.
Gentle pressure
on the shoulders
so as to not startle him,
[Mike]
And a soft kiss on the neck.
[reverend] That hissing,
open flame
is deadlier than
any snake.
Charlie knew it.
Every man who works
a torch knows it.
When you come near em,
you come up smooth.
You don't make
any sudden motions.
[Tom]
I have no idea what I'm doing.
[Servo chuckling]
[Crow] Picasso's woman.
Looks like a baboon!
[reverend] This was it.
a phone call for Charlie.
[Mike] Charlie, does fur run
in your family?
[Tom] Someone brought donuts!
[reverend] Yes. Yes.
A boy. Nine pounds. Wow.
[Crow]
I've got great sperm!
[reverend]
You can forgive Charlie
for being excited.
Who wouldn't be?
A newborn father is one
of the most excitable people
in the whole world.
[Crow] Other than the father
at the time of conception.
[reverend]
You can forgive Charlie
for passing out cigars
during work hours
even though he knew
he should've waited 'til lunch.
[Tom]
He should've waited 'til lunch.
[Mike] Ted's awful.
[reverend]
You can even forgive Charlie
for what happened next.
For that one instant
of final, fatal forgetting.
[Tom] Alan Arkin!
[Crow] Why am I welding?
Why would I be welding to this?
I don't no
understand.
[all screaming]
[Mike]
You don't have to hold it there!
[Crow] Hold the phone.
[Crow] Oh, now
he's T-Bone Burnett.
[reverend] You can forgive
Charlie for everything.
And you can understand
how it happened,
[Tom] Yet I want him punished.
[reverend]
How one thing you cannot do.
[Mike]
Put your elbow in your ear?
[reverend] You cannot change it.
It is done.
And there is nothing
you can say to Charlie,
[Crow] Except gentle pressure.
[reverend] He has said it
all to himself, many times.
[Tom] Here, nice puppy.
Here we go.
[reverend] He has said
that he was careless.
that it could've been avoided,
that he knew better.
[Mike] Here's your bottle.
[reverend] That he only forgot
for a second.
One tiny second.
And in every case,
Charlie is right.
But, still the thing is done.
[Crow] I'm over the fence, man.
I'm outta here!
Charlie has never seen
his baby son
[Tom]
Or the five Mrs. Buchanans.
[reverend]
and Charlie never will.
[Mike] So the leading causes
of accidents are joy,
sex and old age?
[reverend] It is written
in the Old Testament,
to each of us,
this allotment of years,
three score and ten.
[Crow] And there's a psalm
about welding.
[reverend] When you add
that up literally,
it says that the days
of our years number 25,567.
A trivial accident
might take away one
or two of those days.
A serious one might take away
a hundred or a thousand.
[Mike] A disastrous one
would be cool to watch.
[reverend] Suddenly, there might
be no days left at all.
[Tom] America's favorite
deacon of death.
[Crow] Hey! We-- we're trying
to film here!
[reverend]
The Lord has allotted them.
Let not man
by his thoughtlessness
diminish the blessings
of the Lord.
[Mike] Ironically, the reverend
was maimed and crippled
giving communion.
[Tom] Reverend, I'm having a
crisis of faith.
What should I do?
[Crow]
Get safety goggles, my son.
[Mike] Remember to worship at
the railroad of your choice.
[doors closing]
You know, that-- that short
had a interesting juxtaposition.
On the one hand, got lots
of valuable safety information,
-Sure.
-and on the other hand,
it made me want to kill myself.
[laughing]
But you-- you've taken
that information to heart,
haven't you?
Oh-- oh, that's--
that's right, Mike.
Uh-- uh, what was that thing
I was supposed to remember?
Uh, Gentile pray-sure,
gentleben, gentle on my--
No. No. No.
Gentle pressure.
-Gentle pressure.
-Gentle, Gentle pressure.
Can't stress that enough.
Gentle pressure.
I got it! Gentle pressure.
That's right. Gentle pressure.
Now, as it happens,
uh, Tom Servo is doing
some welding on the other side
of this show.
As it happens,
completely coincidentally,
so go over and get
his attention, using
-gentle pressure.
-Gentle pressure.
Don't worry, Mike.
[laughing]
I won't forget that.
Gentle pressure.
[Crow] Hey, Servo, how's you--
[Crow screaming]
Gentle what, Mike?
Crow T. Robot.
He's always getting
into one scrape after another.
[theme music playing]
-[Tom] I'm sorry, Crow.
-[Crow] It happens.
[music playing]
[Tom] The Untouchables!
[Tom]
MCP, Most Crappiest Productions.
[laughing]
[Crow] I hope there's more
accidents in this movie.
[Tom] Ladies and Gentlemen,
Mitzi Gaynor!
[siren blaring]
-[Crow] Another accident!
-[Tom] Oh, no.
[gunfire]
[Mike] Newt Gingrich's America.
[Tom] That's one stressful
Hollywood premier.
[Crow] The family Von Trapp.
[mimicing gunfire]
-[shots firing]
-[sirens blaring]
[Mike] Yes. Yes, yes.
[Crow]
-Zing, -rent, -ent...
[Mike]
Am I that amazingly transparent?
[all laughing]
[Crow]
The names have been changed
to protect the visible.
[Tom]
How can a woman be Kevin Kelly!
[Mike] Oh, no. Cops.
[Crow] There are signs of
water damage on the credits.
[Tom] ♪ Here we come, with our
movie, with the screenplay ♪
by Jack Lewis...
[Mike] Music calks
the scenes together, ca--
-Calker.
-[Tom] Yes.
-[Mike] It's calks.
[Crow] I'm glad it's not
the annoying transparent man.
[all laughing]
[Tom] Credits background
by Formica,
the laminate of the future.
Hey, it's got
photographic effects.
[Mike] What they mean
by photographic effects
is that they filmed it.
-[Crow]Ah!
-[Tom] Ah!
[Mike] Ah, nobody did Hamlet
like Lester Guthrie.
[Tom] This is a modern dress
amazing transparent.
[Crow] And now, William Wegman's
Mein Kampf.
[Servo panting]
[Tom] I'm really a cat person.
-[Mike] Hey, who's walking who?
-[all laughing]
[Crow] I am a fugitive
from a Gulf station.
[dogs barking]
[Tom] So, the cops
have a dogwalking service.
[Mike] Must escape
from Barbra Woodhouse.
[Crow] Peekaboo.
[Tom] Yeah, it's one of them
horseless carriagers.
[Mike] It was nice of his mom
to pick him up
after prison escape practice.
[Crow] Is this one
of the photographic effects?
[Mike] Dogs are gonna flag down
a Buick and give chase.
[all laughing]
[Tom] Whoa. Ten minutes out
of prison and he scores.
[Crow] Hayley Mills in the
Amazing Transparent Trap.
[Tom] Oh wow.
[Mike]
Not really adjusting to society,
would you take me back
to prison?
[Tom] ♪ Hold on
Putting on a top hat ♪
♪ Dusting off my white tie
Breaking out of jail ♪
[music playing]
[Mike] Trip's getting
better and better.
[Crow]
I'm lonely, please love me.
[Tom]
Ah, now you can barely see him.
Camouflocking.
[Mike] Shadowlands 2:
Escape From Oxford.
[Servo laughing]
[Laura] What is it officer?
[Tom]
Is your knob turned to Bob?
A man escaped
from state prison ma'am.
This is just routine.
Who are you
and where have you been?
Oh my name's Matson.
Laura Matson.
This is my husband, John.
We've been to a party
at Pritchards Point.
-I'm afraid he overdid it.
-[Mike] He's a Kennedy.
Uh. May I check
your drivers license, please?
Yes, of course.
[Tom] He's a druggie.
[crickets chirping]
-[Crow] You don't weigh 110..
-What about your husband's?
[Laura] Well that's why,
I'm playing chauffeur. His--
His license was suspended,
uh, drunk driving.
[Tom]
That happened to me, too.
Well, there's no need
to bother him.
He's had enough trouble
for one night
without waking up
and staring into the badge
of an officer.
Very sorry
to have inconvenienced you.
That's quite alright.
[Tom] Just proceed
to next ineffectual policeman.
I think their roadblocks
are too close.
[Tom]
♪ He's amazing and amusing ♪
♪ He's delicious
and nutritious ♪
♪ Two for breakfast, one for ♪
You played it smarter
than I thought you would,
you'd pull that gun,
it would've been all over.
Still don't get it.
Why'd you break me out?
[Mike]
You are Earl, aren't you?
You'll find out when we get
where we're going.
[Crow] She's taking him to
a surprise welcome home party.
-[music playing]
-[Servo humming]
[Tom] You know, North Dakota
film industry never
really took off.
-[Servo humming]
-[Crow] Dorothy returns home.
[Mike] They're on their way
to my grandma's.
I don't need to see this.
[Crow] The sad thing is that
this is their downtown area.
[music playing]
[Tom] Oh,
It's Mary Tyler Moore's
country apartment.
[Crow] Norman?
[Mike] Ah, heh,
uh, my door?
Are you gonna get my...
'cause really,
I mean, we should be g-- well.
[Crow]
Escaped convicts are so rude.
[Tom] Goes without saying,
get off my land.
You come around here
to scare off visitors?
He serves his purpose.
Yeah. I guess everybody does.
Julian, put the car away,
will you? Is Karl waiting?
Been in there chewing up
the carpet for two hours,
-any trouble?
-No. Joey Faust, this is Julian.
[Tom] Cut your hair, hippie.
I've seen him
before in a police bulletin.
[Tom] And on the cover
of the Rolling Stone.
[Crow] Zing.
[Mike]
Well, they have valet parking.
[Tom] So, Julian,
the scene's over.
It's a-- you wanna just...
-cut any time--
-[Mike] It's over.
-[Tom] Go on, go on. Well,
-[Mike] Go-- go away.
[Crow] Ooh, they've got
Protestant Revival furniture.
[Mike]
Hello, so sorry for your loss.
[Laura] Thank you.
[Krenner]
Well, I was beginning to worry.
Major Krenner, may I present,
Joey Faust.
[Tom] Did we overdress
for North Dakota?
Major.
Does it surprise you,
Mr. Faust?
It's for real?
-What army?
-Well, there have been several.
Take your choice.
Please, Mr. Faust.
It's lovely. What is it?
It's only bit of shrapnel,
it's a keepsake.
[Tom] Gimme. Gimme.
That piece of shrapnel ended
the Major's military career.
[Krenner]
That would be all, Laura.
-[Crow] And his sex life.
-[Krenner] Um,
you did well my dear,
now run along and freshen up
while Mr. Faust
and I discuss business.
If you'll excuse me.
Major.
[Tom] Apparently,
I'm not fresh.
Go ahead. Take off the coat
if you wish.
[Krenner] I know
you'd like an explanation.
[Mike] I'm effeminate
because my mother
was overbearing.
Why did you set up the break?
Well, I can use you.
You have got a reputation
in the underworld somewhat
of a genius when it comes
to opening safes and vaults.
[Crow humming]
They must have dug
that shrapnel out of your head.
What kind of an idiot are you?
Krenner, I can't poke my nose
through a bank door
without getting it blown off.
Every newspaper
in the country's got my picture.
You're bitter, Faust.
Mean and bitter.
You trust no one
and you hate everyone.
You're the kind of man
I need and understand.
I know all about
your background.
[Crow] Your marriage
to Lana Turner, your--
What you know about me,
you couldn't have gotten out
of any newspaper.
Well, I check closely
on all the people I use.
I know about the wife
who turned you in.
-[Servo gasping]
-And the child
you've never been
allowed to see.
[Mike] Ouch. That was mean, Tad.
I'm really vulnerable
right now.
[Mike] Oh.
-I may owe you something...
-[Tom] Something?
But if you ever mention
my daughter's name again
you'll have another hole
in your head, I promise you!
[Tom] Susie. Susie.
Susie. Susie.
-Susie. Susie. Susie. Susie.
-If you wish, Mr. Faust.
Susie. Susie. Susie.
Yes, your background
explains your behavior.
[Tom] Susie. Susie.
[theme music playing]
[Krenner] Now,
we're conducting experiments
requiring fissionable materials.
-[Crow growling]
-[Krenner] Make it real for us.
[Krenner] You'll be well paid.
That's atom bomb stuff.
The government has that locked
up tighter than Fort Knox.
[Krenner] Precisely.
Include me
a long way out, chum.
You're hardly in a position
-to bargain, Mr. Faust.
-[Mike] Bargain, Faust, get it?
-[Crow] Huh? Huh? Uh-huh?
-[Tom] Mm-hmm.
A man with a gun doesn't
have to bargain.
-He gets stuff wholesale.
-[Krenner] True.
[Krenner] I'm certain...
Julian would disagree
with you on that.
[Tom] Yeah, well Julian
can lick-- Oh, hi Julian.
[Faust] What these bullets
will do this time?
It'll rip out your spine
and roll it up like a ball
of string.
What's the score, Krenner?
[Tom]
The Vikings pulled it out.
You'll work for us faithfully,
or you'll be turned over
to the authorities.
I understand there's a reward
of $5000 on your head.
[Servo scoffing]
Just what are these authorities
gonna say
about your part in the break?
[Krenner] The police need know
nothing
of my part in the escape.
You see, they'll also pay me
$5000 for a dead Faust.
[Crow] I must admit that it is
funny, it's not funny ha-ha
but it's droll.
What do you want?
[Krenner]
That'll all be for now, Julian.
[Tom] Go freshen up, Julian.
[Krenner]
Come along to the laboratory.
[Mike]
And hear Alexander's Rag Time--
-You got a lab here?
-Oh yes.
We're completely equipped
for our experiments.
[Crow] We got a grant
from viewers like you.
[Krenner]
I made an extensive search
before selecting this ranch
as an operational base.
[Tom]
That's really interesting.
[water bubbling]
-[Mike] Rhoda, we're coming up
-[Tom] I'm here.
[Crow] Night of the Living
Jerry Stiller.
As you can see, this is quite
a serious business.
Dr. Ulaf.
[Tom]
I'm not looking at my boogers.
[Krenner] Come here.
Yes, Major Krenner.
Doctor Peter Ulaf, Mr. Faust.
Mr. Faust has joined us,
he'll be supplying you with
the vital materials. Dr. Ulaf
is an eminent nuclear scientist.
Would you prepare one
of your subject
for the ray treatment, doctor?
We must impress Mr. Faust
with the end result
of your
highly-acclaimed
scientific labors.
[Tom] Want me to make him
a sandwich, in other words.
Ulaf.
-I've heard the name.
-Undoubtedly, you have.
I was quite fortunate
in convincing him to continue
his work here for me.
-[Servo chuckling]
-[Tom] I'm coy.
Now this vault
is of lead two inches thick.
Contains our
radioactive materials.
[Tom] Get in.
[Krenner] Doctor.
I told you to move this.
The ray could penetrate
this lead like butter
and the whole countryside would
go up in a mushroom cloud.
-There is a lot you want
-We have to change.
Are you ready
for the demonstration?
I am ready.
Krenner.
[Mike]
Ah, would you tie my tie?
I agreed to do
your dirty work for you,
but I got to know
what's going on.
Dr. Ulaf will be glad
to explain.
-[Krenner] Doctor.
-This is the principle of x-ray
-but goes further.
-[Crow] Hmm?
[Dr. Ulaf] X-ray pierces only
the outer shell
of the body to show
what lies beneath.
-[Tom] No, it doesn't.
-This ray neutralizes
all tissue and bone structure
in the body.
[Tom]
Turning you into a pudding pop.
This machine utilizes x-ray
Alpha, Beta, and Omega rays
and ultraviolets.
-[Crow] C'mon sell it.
-Inviting the best effect
and filtering out qualities
which would hinder
-our operations.
-[Tom] Alpha, Beta, my a--
Yeah.
It'd seem more simple
to you after you've seen
what goes on.
[Tom] Donald Nixon ladies
and gentlemen. Donald Nixon.
[Crow] Don't touch me,
you brute.
Why are you so worried
about this box?
[Mike]
Doesn't practice safe sex.
Even a lead shield doesn't
cut off all rays,
it simply strains them.
A considerable system
still gets through.
[Ulaf] Any accidental,
concentration of rays
from this apparatus could set
up a chain reaction
in the materials in the vault.
A nuclear fission could result--
-Doctor.
-[Crow] Honey, I shrunk
the audience's interest.
Come.
[Crow] I'd like to show
you my bidet.
[Mike] Burgess Meredith
is in there reading.
[Tom] Look at that.
Ulaf's picking his nose again.
[Crow] Who wants American cheese
on theirs?
[Tom singing]
♪ I'm not a telephone junkie ♪
♪ There's no action ♪
[Crow] He's gonna use that
guinea pig as a guinea pig.
[Tom singing] ♪ Then some people
will turn you away ♪
-[guinea pig squeaking]
-It's not going to hurt.
[Tom] You're taking away
the best months of my life.
Don't be afraid.
[Tom] Yeah,
why would I be afraid.
This is all perfectly normal.
[Crow] I'm still sore
from the last time.
[Tom] If he straps
on a rubber glove, I'm leaving.
[Mike] I'm just going to check
your back molars.
[Crow] Have a look
at Coco's medical record.
Let's see, whooping cough
in third grade.
Mother ate by cat,
father flushed down toilet,
everything normal.
Ah, he's turning on the
all-vacuum cleaner network.
[Mike] He's inventing a new
kind of toilet float.
[Crow] Kind of an abstract
sculpture of Jayne Mansfield.
[Servo laughing]
[Tom] Don't know what
he's doing but it looks naughty.
-[Servo chuckling]
-[Tom] Nice, huh?
[Crow]
For those of you who missed it,
I'll go through it all again.
[Tom] Need anything, poopy?
Why don't you disrobe
and change into a gown?
[Tom] Ah, close enough there,
gotta turn a few of these knobs.
[Crow] You know hiring nuclear
temps wasn't a good idea.
[Mike] All this just to get
a UHF-station?
[Tom] Auf wiedersehen ,
little poo poo. I love you.
[Crow] Home execution,
Texas style.
[Mike] Now, they're gonna record
a Yes album.
Keep your eye
on the guinea pig.
[Tom] ♪ Keep your eye
on the guinea pig ♪
[all humming]
[music playing]
[Crow] I ain't talking, coppers.
[Mike] So they've come up
with new ways
to off guinea pigs.
[Crow] I'll show
that Oppenheimer.
[music playing]
[Tom] Rocky dies yellow,
killer coward at end.
[Mike] I do believe
in Mighty Mouse, help me!
[Crow] Oh, he's with the William
Morris Agency.
[Tom] Well, that was both
amazing and transparent.
C'mon, Mr. Faust.
[Mike] I'm pretty sure
it's not that radioactive.
[Crow] The gangster nuclear
program
is off to a great start.
[Tom]
We're gonna call him Harvey.
Go ahead, Mr. Faust,
prove to yourself it isn't done
with mirrors.
[Crow] You schnitzel poopy.
[Krenner] You see?
I touch it. it does it no harm.
[Tom] Bogus.
Still have any doubts,
Mr. Faust?
[Mike] Let's see what Picture
Picture's doing.
[all laughing]
No doubts.
You can return the animal
to visibility, doctor.
-Hey, uh,
-[Crow] His girdle is slipping.
What happens to the guinea pig?
Ulaf has perfected the ray
to a point there's
no danger to the subject,
no ill effects at all.
[Tom] It's safe, now quick get
in the vault. Quick.
[Mike] Uh, bless me father for
I have sinned.
[Crow]
Ah, the switching sequence.
You loved it before, you'll
love it again.
[Tom] Oh, yeah, that one.
Now watch from the peephole,
you'll find the guinea pig
is unharmed.
[Mike] You'll be accelerating
the guinea pig to near the speed
of light and collide it
with a copper foil.
[all humming]
[Crow] Let's tell him
he's still invisible.
[all laughing]
[Mike] Think of it. People might
think there's not a guinea pig
in a room,
when there actually is.
[all laughing]
-[Tom] It's all brilliant.
-[Servo chuckling]
[theme music playing]
[Tom] What is going on?
Something big is going down man.
Frank is calling,
it must be really important.
Mike. I wanted to let you know
I won't be in today.
After five years,
Dr. Forrester
is finally giving me a day off.
So needless to say,
don't even bother trying to get
in touch with me today.
Frank, I've never tried
to contact you,
but congratulations
on your day off.
Yeah, after five years you must
have some big plans, huh?
Well, if I seem just
a little bit cocky,
it's for a very good reason.
I've got a ticket to
see Squanto: A Warrior's Tale ,
uh-huh, you heard right.
Squanto.
I've been planning to see
this movie for months
and I wanted
to make sure I got in,
so I bought this ticket
from a scalper for $1000.
I know that sounds
a little steep, but hey,
this is Squanto
I'm talking about.
Well, Clay, I'm off,
to see Squanto .
Frank, Squanto opened and closed
three weeks ago.
Squanto!
Cheer up Frank, maybe uh,
C amp Nowhere is still playing.
Yeah, or Th e Road to Wellville.
[alarm buzzing]
[Mike]
Oh, we got movie sign!
[all laughing]
[doors opening]
-[Mike] Poor little guy.
-[Tom] Yeah, sad, huh?
That should satisfy
your curiosity, Mr. Faust.
As you can no doubt deduce,
such a mechanism
as this has
unlimited possibilities.
-Ah, like what?
-That will come later.
First things first, please.
[Crow] Hey, they could rid
the world of Pauly Shore.
No harm done at all.
Perfectly healthy.
-[Servo buzzing]
-[Tom] Ow!
I imagine you've seen enough
for one day, hmm?
And you certainly must be tired
after your trip.
Yeah, I could use
a little sleep.
I'm sure Julian has found
some clothes that will fit you.
[Mike] We have some lederhosen.
What, uh, is in here?
It's no concern of yours.
C'mon, Mr. Faust.
[Crow] I bet there are all sorts
of invisible
nude chicks in there, huh?
[Tom] Well, you'll be sleeping
with the guinea pigs
I hope you don't mind.
[Mike]
Don't you ever improvise again,
you almost ruined
the second act.
Oh, I'm sorry I yelled.
I shouldn't be gone long.
[Tom] Yup.
Leave the gate open, I'll lock
it when I get back.
[Tom] Yup.
I don't think you need to be
cautioned about Faust.
-[Tom] Yup.
-He's dangerous and,
locks mean nothing to him,
so I want you
where you can watch
his door at all times.
[Tom] Yup.
Keep him in his room,
you understand?
-He won't go nowhere.
-Alright.
[Tom] Oh, and E. Power Biggs
has been spotted,
so guard the organ.
[Mike] I'm gonna
hunt you down, fern.
[Tom] Hey! Give me a crack
at that bowl, huh?
[Servo humming]
[Crow] St. Joseph aspirin
for gangsters.
[Mike singing] ♪ Take the ribbon
from your hair ♪
[Tom] Oh, I just rolled
on a guinea pig. Ugh.
[Crow] Oh good, he's asleep.
I can put out the presents.
[Mike] Oh, I have a rich life.
[Tom] Now, it's just me
and the latest issue of Sassy .
[Crow] I wish I didn't know
there was pizza rolls
in the fridge.
[Tom] I wish I were back
in prison.
I miss my wife, Jake.
[Mike] That's cute,
I could wear that.
[Crow] You were talking to me,
weren't you?
You said come over here,
I'm lonely. Drink me, please.
Well, little friend.
[Tom]
Yup. Here's to transparencies.
[Servo gulping]
[Crow] These are not
comfortable jammies.
[Mike]
Well, back to my novel.
[Tom] Door handles
mean nothing to me.
[Mike] Goofus pisses me off.
[Crow] Ah, Listermint.
[all laughing]
[Tom] Alright,
I better go fall for this.
Locks may mean nothing
to you, mister,
but a lock saved my life once.
Faust?
[Crow] You rubbing a glass
against the wall?
You in there, Faust?
[Tom] I was trying
to read Anna Quindlen.
[Mike] Mr. Wilson and Dennis
the Menace: The Final Conflict.
[Crow]
And I get to keep the glass.
[Tom] We'll turn this
into a bolero jacket.
Quit drooling
on the carpet. Hey.
[Servo slurping]
-[music playing]
-[Servo humming]
[Crow] I'm breaking all the
guinea pigs out of this place.
[Tom] I just got to find that
Snap-on Tools calendar.
[Mike] This place is probably
crawling
with whiskery old guards.
[Crow] He's gonna hide
Easter baskets now.
[Tom] Bud, Princess, Beaver,
Wally, Robbie, Chip, Ernie.
[Mike] Hey!
This is not my beautiful house.
Doctor Ulaf.
[Tom] You know what,
I'm going to rearrange?
[Crow] That screen is
so the guinea pig can undress.
[Tom]
This lock has meaning to me.
[Mike] There's gotta be a glass
I can rub against this door.
[Crow]
I'm feeling good right now.
♪ Scooby dooby dooby doo ♪
[Tom] I just have this craving
for some Sociables.
[Mike]
Now, I can sew that button on.
[Crow] Time to slip into
something more comfortable.
[Tom]
Surprise! Happy birthday to you.
What are you doing?
What is it you want up here?
Take it easy, doc.
I just came up to see you.
Thought maybe,
they had you locked up in there.
Not I. Only what's left
of my soul.
-[Tom] I'm kidding, anyway.
-I need to get some answers.
You seem 'bout the only one
around here
who isn't a member
of Krenner's fan club.
I have nothing to say.
I'm a servant.
Major Krenner does my thinking
for me.
[Crow] Hm, his robe
is by Lands of Austria. Wow.
What's he got on you, doc?
[Tom] He knows I'm German.
-Why do you ask me these things?
-So I can get some answers!
How'd you get mixed up in this?
My daughter. He's holding her.
In that cheese box?
Well, open it up
and let her out.
Please Mr. Faust, I do not joke.
Not about my daughter.
[Tom] Although I hear
she swims out to troop ships.
[Servo laughing]
But that's a joke.
[Mike] That hurt, if it makes
you feel good to hurt me
-then so be it.
-Alright, doc.
Start at the beginning
how'd you get over here?
[Crow] We carpooled
from the Ottoman Empire.
At the end of Second World War,
I fled my own country
-with my baby daughter.
-[Servo humming]
My wife had died of experiments,
I had been forced
to perform on her
-in the concentration camp.
-Your own wife?
All my patients wore hoods,
I couldn't see their faces.
I didn't know my wife was one
of them until it was too late.
[Mike] I bet this place is loud
in a rainstorm.
It still don't explain
how you got here.
-[Crow] I took a damn boat!
-I came to this country
as a refugee. No one knew
I was a scientist.
-Except spies like Krenner.
-[Tom] Spies like us.
After my wife died, I wanted no
more of science,
-Spies like us!
-I decided to come here.
-[Servo laughing]
-[Mike] It's not funny.
-Here's your daughter?
-[Tom] Spies like us!
If I do not do as I'm told,
she will be killed.
-[Tom] Spies like us!
-If I carry out the orders,
-she isn't killed.
-[Servo coughing]
[Tom] Hey, let's go spy
on the guinea pigs
-while they take their showers.
-...that you could open it.
Not now, doc. I got problems.
Please, Mr. Faust,
release my daughter
and take her to some safe place.
Knock it off, doc,
I got my own troubles.
Then you can't open it.
I could open
that thing blindfolded.
[Mike] I'll open it,
but locks mean nothing to me.
Hmm. Quite the little
psychologist, aren't ya, doc?
That's good reasoning.
[Crow] Dear God, its Kitty
Carlisle and she's packing heat!
[Tom] Oh, congratulations
on your wedding, Miss Havisham.
[Crow]
Certainly a daring nightgown.
-[Mike] Rated to 30 below.
-Downstairs, Faust.
And please try not
to be amusing.
[Tom] Hey don't worry.
No problem on this end.
Good night, Doctor Ulaf.
[Crow]
Say good night to my hamsters.
[Servo sobbing]
[Tom] I love this door.
Is this a panel craft?
[Servo sobbing]
[Tom]
I love a well-armed woman.
[Mike] Sit down at that organ
and play Stardust.
[Crow]
Arnold Schwarzenegger, pregnant.
[Tom] Oh, he grabs his neck
more than Chuck Heston.
What's next Mata Hari,
you gonna shoot me?
Krenner probably will
when he gets back.
He doesn't
appreciate disloyalty.
-[Mike] He hates Jack Morris.
-Julian's the loyal type.
[Tom] And bitter.
All it got him was a lump
in the head.
-[Crow] Backgammon?
-He's still out.
I couldn't bring him around.
[Tom] See? He's pregnant.
I can't believe it.
[Laura] What's on your mind?
For a dame that's supposed
to be so greedy,
you don't know anything
about playing a hole card.
Oh?
Ever think how much that ray
would be worth to a guy
-who wanted to rob a bank?
-[Mike] With a team of hamsters?
With that thing, I could get
into every vault
in the country
in broad daylight.
Dream on, buster.
-[Tom] I hate that show.
-Sounds pretty.
Of course, to take
on jobs like that,
a fella'd have
to have a little help.
Now, splitting the take
of a few of those
would pay you a lot more
than Krenner will ever give you
in a lifetime.
[Crow] He gives me
a million dollars a day.
You need background music
for this commercial.
Full orchestra and violin.
-[Mike] Maybe Bobby McFerrin.
-Don't believe me.
Don't be a gambler.
Should I gamble on
having my throat slit by Krenner
or being shot by you?
-[Crow] Go for the curtain!
-Honey, that's a chance
you'd have to take,
Just like the risk
I run every time
I get under that ray.
Well, if you don't take
a chance, you'll never know.
[Crow] That's in The Road
Less Traveled.
I'll keep it in mind.
-[Crow] It's under control Hank.
-Thanks Julian.
He-- he was trying
to make a deal.
You must have heard
what he said.
He was talking a double-cross.
Yeah, I heard him.
Sounded like you were listening
awful close, too.
[Tom]
She's got Ernest Borgnine arms.
Keep quiet about this, Julian.
-Keep quiet and I'll help you.
-[Crow] With your math.
You know that Krenner's gonna
blame you
for letting him
out of his room.
We've got to help
each other now.
-[door knocking]
-[Krenner] Julian.
-[Tom] Lucy, I'm home!
[Julian]
Let's get him in the room.
-[door knocking]
-[Krenner] Julian!
[Tom] Action Protection league,
let us in!
-[door knocking]
-[Julian] I'm coming.
-Julian! Open this door.
[Crow] Give someone else
a crack of this house.
What happened?
-Where were you?
-[Mike] We had a date.
Getting the broom.
Wanted to sweep
up that bottle I dropped.
I told you not to take
your eyes off of Faust's door.
Oh, him. He's out cold.
I went in, picked up the bottle,
figured you didn't want him
nipping in the morning
when he wakes up.
[Tom] Want some griddle cakes?
[Krenner] You did right.
He's got to be sober.
Good night.
-Night.
-[Mike] Night, Herr Goebbels.
Yeah, I broke one
of the gophers earlier, sorry.
[Tom] The organ plays
a pivotal part in this movie,
doesn't it?
-[Crow] Why'd you gob on me?
-What you do that for?
Save your own skin?
[Crow] My skin is beyond saving.
This idea
of yours does interest me.
I figure you need me
more than I need you.
[Tom] Baby, I'm-a need you.
[Mike humming
"Addams Family" theme]
[Crow] Good morning.
[Tom] Yeah. Breakfast
with Dorothy Parker.
[Mike] Gotta get out
and cut hay but first, a gimlet.
[Tom] Seems to be a kind
of a dark side to this house.
[Crow]
I can't stand the tension,
somebody play that organ!
[Mike]
Where's that olive I was saving?
I thought you were up
in the lab.
[Tom] I was.
-What was that for?
-Stop trying.
Don't even think about it.
Julian told me about your talk
-with Faust.
-[Crow] Don't even think
about asking me
if I was up in the lab.
-Didn't make any deal.
-No, not yet.
But I know you.
My memory is too good.
I remember our other deals.
You don't think I
gave you enough
of a share, do you?
What are you talking about?
What could I possibly have
in common with Faust?
-He's a hood.
-Just the type you go for.
Laura, I don't care
what you do with your life
but when it interferes
with my plans, I draw the line.
[Mike]
I want you to go to college.
[Crow]
You were about to ask me
if I was up in the lab again,
weren't you?
Lay off the vodka. I want
you ready when I need you.
[Tom]
♪ As long as he needs me. ♪
Well, how about some coffee?
If you will relax, Mr. Faust,
there will be no pain.
You may lose consciousness
for a few moments
after you become invisible, but
there should
be no other ill effect.
How do you know
it'll work on a human?
Do you know what'll happen?
We made hundreds
of such experiments,
there can be no slip-up.
[Tom]
Unless something goes wrong.
Come on, doctor, we don't
have all night.
[Crow] David McCallum was booked
for midnight.
[Mike] We were just in the lab,
weren't we?
-[Servo mimics slap]
-[Mike] Aah!
[Mike] Is that the toner up
there for the--
when they make people
visible again?
[Crow humming]
[Crow] Nothing to worry about.
[Tom] I'm in kind of a rush
today,
so, I pushed fewer buttons.
[Mike] Ah, gentle pressure.
[Crow] Oh, he's a thick man.
[Tom] I don't like peering up
his nostrils, though.
[Tom] Isn't someone gonna
swab me with antiseptic?
[Mike] Please?
[Crow] It's just going to make
a little hamster-size
invisible hole
in the middle of 'em.
[Tom] Look at that one, Henry.
It's the biggest guinea pig
I ever saw.
[Mike] Accept the pain, man,
I've sucked up
a lot more radiation
than you ever will, chunky boy.
[Crow] The visible six banger.
You build it.
[Servo growling]
[Mike] My pancreas!
[Crow] He disappeared
with an audible ping.
He's going to Notions!
[theme music playing]
[Mike]
Wow. He leaves quite an odor.
What's happened? Is he alright?
[Crow] Doc,
that's not his wrist.
His pulse is quite rapid,
but that is to be expected.
-Why is he breathing like that?
-It may be shock.
Faust, can you hear me?
Can you speak?
Faust, try to sit up.
[Tom]
Talking to the wrong end.
He stopped breathing.
Well, do something!
[Crow] Don't do that!
-He's gone.
-What?
[gasping]
-[Crow] He gave me a wet Willie.
-It's Faust. He's here.
Faust, answer me, you--
[grunting]
[Crow] I found him.
[Crow laughing]
Faust, listen to me,
you'll remain invisible
until I want to turn it off,
so you--
[Crow]
There's a guinea pig on my neck!
[Mike] That's some form
of pure energy, Captain.
[Faust]
If I choke you hard enough,
you'll bring me back.
[Tom] Boy, the worst
a guinea pig
ever did
was piddle on him.
[Faust] I'm just showing you
how badly you need me
-and my loyalty costs money.
-[Crow] Oh, sorry Ollie.
I told you you'd be well paid.
[Faust] You neglected one thing,
chum, how much?
-A thousand dollars.
-[Faust laughing]
A thousand every time you do
a job.
[Faust] Krenner, if I'm gonna
be hit, I want money.
Lots of money.
What do you expect?
I can't pay--
[Faust] Oh yes, you can, Major.
I'm sure you can.
[Tom] Oh, you're gonna
pay me, Norton.
[Faust] We can talk it
over in private. Downstairs?
[Mike] Good idea. The hamsters
are trying to sleep up here.
[Faust] Over here Major.
I'm waiting.
[Crow] As it's implied that
I'm over here.
After you, Major.
[Tom] I'm so invisible right now
I've never been
less not invisible.
[laughing]
[Mike] Damn you all to hell.
Anyway.
So you don't think a thousand
is enough, hmm?
[Crow] Hang on, I'm snagged
on the banister.
[Faust]
You're a real case, Major.
You think everyone's supposed
to jump when you open
your big, fat mouth. Well,
you've forgotten one thing.
-[Mike] Your purse.
-Forgotten what?
[Faust] You gotta have me.
[Tom]
♪ You gotta have heart. ♪
[Faust] Now whatever you're
up to, I'm worth plenty to you,
or you wouldn't have gone to
all that trouble of
breaking me out?
You're a dead duck without me.
-[Crow] Am I on speakerphone?
-What do you have in mind?
[Faust] Well, walking
into that nuclear bomb's worth
about 25 grand.
[Tom] Oh, Abbott, I--
[Faust]
Get a little air in here.
Twenty five grand, you're--
you're mad! I don't have
-that kind of money.
-Then you do the job, Major.
[Tom] I'm scratching
my butt right now, you know.
[Faust] That's the figure,
25 grand in small bills,
C.O.D., take it or leave it.
-[Crow] Your fly's open.
-All right.
You'll go tonight.
Laura will drive you.
[Tom]
What, you made transparent men
by the millions, Pittsburgh.
[Mike] Oppenheimer cupped
Einstein's breasts
as Niels Bohr let his smock slip
to the lab floor.
Oh, this is hot.
[Crow] Jeannie.
[Tom] I don't get science.
[Mike] Is that Brut?
[Crow] Well I suppose
they do those things.
[Tom]
Hey, when you're transparent,
mess with a fuse box.
It's funny.
[Mike] You can't put
a hot tub in here,
you need at least 100 amps.
[Crow] That's not really worth
standing up for, but I'm up.
[Tom] Wheel Of Fortune!
[Mike] Why does he have
a napkin dispenser?
[Tom] I don't--
Great. Here comes Chaz the Spaz.
No, I will not trade lunches
with you, Chaz.
[Mike]
My cigarette lacks flavor.
What's wrong with you?
I don't know. Why, I just
thought I heard something.
[Crow] Aye, matey. Hard to port!
[Crow humming]
Back in ten minutes.
I gotta check the other post.
[Mike] Yeah, right, light
a match, will ya?
[music playing]
[Tom] Don't-- Jeez,
they should lock that thing.
[Crow] He's moshing by himself.
[Mike] This happens every day
whether there's an invisible man
or not.
[Crow mimics dog yelping]
[Mike] No, he's stealing
their walleye minnows.
[Tom]
Or maybe he should've brought
a transparent tote bag.
[Crow] Be sure to sign out.
[Mike] Is he gonna plant bulbs?
[Crow] Here,
they're just flexing
their special effects muscles.
[Tom]
Gerry Cooney, security guard.
[Tom singing] ♪ Put a hundred
down and buy a car ♪
You didn't see anyone
during all this?
Well, no sir. I--
I heard a clicking noise
like the wheel of the vault
was turning, and I--
I told him about it but neither
one of us saw anything.
That's right, there was nothing
when I started to check
the other guard post.
[Crow]
I don't live with my mother.
Then what?
Well, I-- I turned around and a,
and the vault door was open,
all by itself and--
and I got up to check it
and-- and I pulled my gun.
And something was all over me
and then the next thing I know,
-I'm-- I'm waking up.
-[Tom] Uh-huh.
What about the alarm panel,
when did it get wrecked?
I don't know, Mr. Drake,
it was okay when I came on duty.
It couldn't have happened while
I was checking posts
or he'd have noticed anyone
tampering with it.
It's set up with each of us
covering the other.
Yes, but it's quite obvious,
neither one of you were covering
the other. In fact,
there was no coverage at all.
[Tom] Can we
finish being fired?
[Mike]
There's a little stormtrooper
who lives in my pants.
He whispers things to me.
Alright, doctor, what was it
that you wanted to tell me
about the guinea pig?
-It was only a matter of time.
-[Crow] I've grown to love him.
It died despite
of resistance it was developing
-against radiation,
-[Tom] She lived a good life.
What about Faust?
It's too early to tell
but each time
it will take longer to reduce
him to invisibility, less to
return him to normal states.
He will also develop
a resistance.
What about the new material,
the X-13?
I need more time to study it.
Its properties are different
from other nuclear materials.
I do not like keeping it here.
It's bombardment ratio
is also much lower,
-[Mike] It's vomit ratio?
-[Tom] Vova-- Vobamat.
-Strawberry jam.
-Uh,
-afraid of an explosion?
-Yes.
[Tom] Unt I'm afraid of strudel,
though, I don't know why.
-It's --
-Well use the X-13 on Faust.
It could mean his death.
Doctor, I'm not concerned with
the welfare of one man.
I must know the full potential
of your invention
because my aim is to make
an entire army invisible,
do you understand?
An entire army.
I did not agree to kill a man
by deliberate
radiation poisoning.
You're too old-fashioned
to be a genius.
[doors closing]
-Say Mike. What do we have here?
-Yeah, it looks really cool.
Whatever it is.
Oh, come on, it's my
Magichord 2000
Lowrey electronic organ.
Pretty neat, huh?
-I'll say.
-What'd it do?
Oh well, give
a listen. Here.
[organ playing]
This is neat.
This will be fun forever.
-We'll never get sick of this.
-No, uh.
Say Tom, I've got,
three rubber bands in my room.
-I'm there man.
-Huh, huh? Okay, let's go.
[organ playing]
Cambot. Lights please.
Ah, perfect.
Perhaps the most volatile
and feisty
of Henry the VIII's six wives
was Anne Boleyn.
[organ playing]
What are you-- Hi.
Just, uh, putting on, uh,
doing some uh,
Lights please, Cambot.
I was just-- let me get--
Latin rhythm.
-Oh.
-We'll be right back.
-Yeah, I was just uh--
-Yeah, sure.
-Something I heard.
-We know.
Nothing we haven't done.
[organ playing]
-[Crow laughing]
-[Mike] Rick quick, I was--
Something every
cheap safecracker
in the country's been
dreaming of.
Too bad the doc didn't invent
it years ago
for the right people.
Wouldn't be cooped up here now.
[Crow] Give me five, homey.
You better lay off
the giggle water.
He can't use you drunk,
you know.
It's a case of my using him,
now come on with a drink.
[Tom] What am I,
invisible here?
I could have walked
into that vault
in broad daylight,
had done the same thing.
So easy, I felt like
I was taking Krenner's
-money away from him.
-[Crow] Hi pop!
This time you do
it the hard way.
-In daylight.
-[Mike] On stilts.
Well, through with me
so soon, huh?
-Gonna get me killed off.
-Oh, no not at all.
But I have learned that security
has been tripled
on the
vaults during the night shift.
Six men. But it hasn't been
strengthened during the day.
Since where do you get
these gems?
He has sources,
you better believe it.
One more haul,
and we'll have enough
for our present supply
of work. Uh-uh.
-[Tom] Not the Glenfiddich.
-You won't need this,
-we're ready in the lab.
-[Crow] Thanks a lot, Bill W.
[Mike] Did I do something wrong
to make him not slap me?
My girdle is killing me.
[Crow] Mr. Keisterman's mailbox.
[Mike] You see, doctor,
my mom loved my sister
a lot more than me and...
[Tom] Tonight on 21, Charles Van
Doren vs. Leopold Stokowski.
[Crow] Go ahead
on invisible booth five.
Hurry up.
[Mike] You've been riding
my tuchis for too long.
[Tom] Oliver Reed's
looking better than usual.
I cannot.
[Crow] That bratwurst
is repeating on me.
[Mike] I guess,
I could've done that.
[Tom] It didn't seem too hard.
Great. A guinea pig got me.
[Mike] I'll make any one
invisible for $49.95.
[Crow] Well, either he's
invisible or the rice is done.
[Tom] Forestry, changing the
face of northern Michigan.
[Mike] Jackie Kennedy,
after the tragedy.
She just took off
in the convertible.
[Tom] Took a little cruise.
You can't get away with
this in broad daylight, Joey.
Why don't you stop running
Kranner's errands?
-[Crow] I'm naked you know.
-Lets not get any more involved.
[Faust]
Don't get emotional baby,
you're nice as a playmate.
Let's keep it that way.
Let's understand that, hmm?
They may not see you,
but they're
bound to see the lead container
when you try to get it out.
[Faust] Got it all wrong, honey.
Today's the day
we take the bank.
In broad daylight? You're crazy!
[Faust] You're talking
to a professional, remember?
I don't have to worry
about time locks
or anything like that.
Just walk in, pack up
the loose cash, and walk out
and you, sweetheart,
are gonna be waiting for me.
[Crow] That guy just lights up
the screen.
Oh, don't even say it.
You'll cut'll be forty percent.
[Tom] Chief, there's an
invisible man to see you.
[Faust] I'll have to climb out.
[Crow] See? I climbed out.
[Mike] I'll have to walk
into the bank.
And now the lighter side
of banking.
[Crow] Oh, that door
is on the fritz, I'll fix that.
[Tom] Goodness, the steaks
and chops are calling me.
[Mike] Anyone would notice
if I got a nice big porterhouse
and brought it back in here.
[Crow] Rod Serling.
[Tom] A deposit, submitted
for your approval.
[Mike] Guess that line's
for women only.
Eliza Doolittle.
[Tom] Well, "Beginner's Guide
to Bank Security".
[Mike] Joey's gonna steal
everybody's real
estate abstract.
[Tom] No.
[Crow]
That's a tiny ping pong table.
[Tom] Hey, Kevin Costner
as Jim Garrison.
Wait.
[Mike]
She's very Olivia da Havilland.
[Tom] All this happened
in Point Break
only you could see everyone.
-[Mike] Unfortunately,
-[Crow] Oh, great.
I'm just transparent-ish.
-Oh my Lord.
-[Tom] It's Donald Nixon.
Don't anybody move,
you won't get hurt.
[Crow] He'd be less conspicuous
without the gun and the money.
What's the matter?
What changed?
Drive. Drive. Drive!
[Mike] What's the matter?
I oughta--
[Tom] I just know I'm gonna show
up in News of the Weird now.
[Mike] No blinker. They're
just exacerbating their crime.
Thank you very much
for your cooperation, Miss.
-I only hope it does some good.
-I'm sure it will.
-[phone ringing]
-[Tom] He was invisible
-but I'm positive he was black.
-Security.
Good day now.
[Tom] He's been downgraded
to a partially-visible man.
Okay.
Guess we can't stop it now.
[Tom]
Someone ordered pizza for us.
Story's out. A reporter
was at the police station
when the alarm came in.
Well, there's no doubt
it was Faust.
Everyone
at the bank's identified him.
Well, what can we do?
The man makes himself invisible.
Locks mean nothing to him.
-[Tom] He's smarter than us.
-He did take the X-13.
What defense do
we have against him?
Nothing. None.
[Tom] Maybe cops on bicycles
is the answer.
[Mike]
We return now to Paris, Texas.
Hold it here.
[Crow] I love the smell of
atrazine in the morning.
[Tom] Oh, looks like he made
the trip to bountiful.
[hissing]
[Tom] I'm gonna build a casino,
right here.
There must be something
we can do.
Now, if I can just
get down to Ulaf.
I can't get back to the house
till I'm invisible again.
[radio jockey] Police,
report the so-called
invisible man who robbed
the Coatesville national bank
has been identified
as Joey Faust,
escaped convict
and safe cracker.
Witnesses said the robber became
visible before their eyes.
Citizens are warn--
[Crow] I wanted to listen
to the Twins.
He's gotta come back,
and that tramp, too.
I'll teach them
to double-cross me.
Take my bags outside and watch
for them.
-Right.
-[Mike] My own personal MacLeod.
[Tom] This gives me a chance
to call Peggy, quick.
I know some people in Mexico.
We can go there
and start all over again.
[Tom] Mexico, huh?
Do you know Jose.
I know what I've been,
Joey, but--
-I can change all that.
-[Crow] I can be taller.
-More full-figured.
-What are you doing?
Giving you your split.
You're on your own, baby.
But-- but you said
we'd be together.
Honey, right now, I need a car
more than I need you.
So you can start walking
any time.
But you can't just go off
and leave me.
[Mike]
I'll be right back after this.
Joey!
[Tom] He overdid
the Clearasil again.
-[Faust] Goodbye, Laura.
-[Crow] I tell you, I love you.
[Crow] Huh. Is this goodbye?
[Tom] It's a fine
how-do-you-do.
Oh, well, at least he left me
this pound of ground beef.
Some patties, I suppose.
[Mike] Oh, I gotta get
the soybeans in.
We'll leave everything except
the nuclear material.
[Crow] Nuke-u-lar!
The police catch Faust
and hear his story,
they'll be all over us.
[Crow] Oh, my Zeitgeist
is gestalting
and now I have middle Schmitz.
I will not.
-What?
-[Tom] Uh, okay I will.
I have been running away most
of my life.
[Crow] Now get out of my
dingy furnished laboratory.
Doctor,
there's something wrong
with your formula.
But, we'll work it out
in a new location.
An invisible army
is worth billions.
An army of dead men, Major.
[Mike] Oh, thanks,
Otto Von Bringmedown.
[laughing]
I'm taking Marie with me,
I'm sure you'll come along.
No!
[Crow]
She didn't finish her supper
-she should stay in her room.
-Marie, my dear.
Prison is fun.
[Mike] What the-- huh?
[Krenner] Faust! Let me out
of here!
[Crow] It's super Donald Nixon.
Doc, what's wrong? Why do I keep
appearing and disappearing?
I don't know.
I needed more time to study
the X-13 before trying
it out on you,
Oh, fine.
Well, you're gonna do something
about it.
I've got to be normal,
you're gonna take care of it.
I will, but not in this place.
Oh, why not?
I got him locked up.
I want to be taken away
from here,
my daughter and I, only then,
I will treat you.
-But--
-[Tom] You with th-- then the--
Alright, lets blow out of here.
[Crow] Lets put our lips
together and blow.
[Tom]
So why is she dressed for mass?
[Mike] Man, Houdini couldn't get
her out of that dress.
-[Julian] Forget something?
-[Crow] Uh, girdles.
[theme music playing]
Put that thing down.
I take my orders from the Major.
I have to.
-The maj--
-Let me.
Julian,
You believe what he told you
about your son being alive
in prison and in Europe?
-Yes I do.
-You're a fool.
Your son's dead, Julian.
Krenner's been using
you all along.
[Tom]
But he is in Europe, right?
[Mike] I don't even have a son.
I'm so stupid.
[Crow] I've guarded this organ
for five years.
Suddenly I'm back story.
She's right.
So you had to
come back. Come on.
[Mike] I hate to see
a grown codger cry.
Told you to hit the road,
it was for your own good.
But, Joey please,
please give me a chance.
Sweetheart, you had
your chance. In.
[Crow] This guy loves locks.
Let's admit it.
All right, come on.
Come on, Julian.
[Crow] We are all going
to grandma's
and we're all going
to have a good time!
[Tom] Julian. See?
Do you know Krenner is after
a process so an invisible army
-can invade your country .
-[Mike] Get off me.
I don't care about Krenner
or his army, I care about me.
Then all of this is futile.
Krenner has found me before.
He'll find me again.
I've got money. I know places
across the border
he never heard of.
How long are these treatments
-gonna take?
-You may someday be declared
a martyr, Mr. Faust.
A man who sacrificed himself
so that an invisible army
might not overrun your country!
What are you trying to pull,
you wanted out of here,
I made a deal with you, now
you cross me and I'll kill you.
I'm a dying man, Mr. Faust.
Radiation poisoning.
-[Mike] Oh, boo-hoo.
-You're dying, too.
-You're worse off than I am.
-You're lying.
You have only weeks,
perhaps days, to live.
[Crow]
Damn you, Uncle Charlie!
You used me to get away
from Krenner.
To free Maria.
I had no choice.
[Mike]
That's one big cow flop.
C'mon.
Are you so intent
upon evading the police
for a few remaining days?
Don't you care
what Krenner is doing
-to your country.
-Why should I care?
What did my country ever do
for me but try and bury me
in a concrete tomb for the rest
of my life!
[Crow] Oh, your breath
is not invisible.
I think only of my child.
You should think of yours.
Perhaps you deserve prison.
But did Maria deserve
what has happened to her?
Did her mother need to die?
Is this the kind of world
you want for your child?
That is what an invisible army
would bring. I've seen it!
[Crow speaking gibberish]
How much longer I got?
A month.
No more.
[Tom] So, no sense
in starting a Michener novel.
[Mike] Here. I sneezed
into that.
[Crow] It's Big League Chew.
Don't wait for me.
[Tom] I'm gonna do me
a little possum hunting.
Then I'll meet up with you.
[Mike] This amazing
transparent man stands to win--
[Crow] Where have you been?
There's a man who has unlocked
every door
except the one to his own soul.
[Tom] Bob Dornan.
Now he has the key.
Come, my dear, we must find
a telephone
-and notify the police.
-[Tom] Daddy,
could I have a line
at some point?
[gunfire]
[Crow] It's open.
[gunshot]
[Mike] There.
[Laura] Joey!
-[door knocking]
-[Laura] Joey!
[Tom]
This marathon bar is chewy.
[Laura] Joey!
Joey will you please,
listen to me--
Wait for me outside.
[gunshots]
[Mike] Now see, I told you
to wait for me outside.
[Crow] I'll prop your head
up so you can watch Sullivan.
[Tom] Okay, you guard
the downstairs now.
[Mike] The irony of the organ
being there is unbelievable.
[Tom] You shot the only woman
who ever vaguely loved me.
[Crow]
This is gonna be so great.
[Mike] You're it. No tag-backs.
[Tom] Oh, no. It was a bottle
of Jolt Cola.
[Crow] With each blow he
looks more like James Garner.
[Mike] Okay, now would be a
good time
for me to turn transparent.
[Tom] I'll scrape your scapula
down 'til there's nothing left.
-You crushed my cookies.
-[Crow] I'm sorry our hygienist
called in sick, again.
[Tom] Just takes a minute
so if you just lay there,
I'll be killing you shortly.
Just hang on.
[Mike] You want a pop or
anything, I'm in the fridge?
[Crow] Thought I was done,
but just a few more minutes.
[Tom] Just got
to get the instructions.
Do you remember
how this thing works?
[Crow]
You brute, you brute, you brute,
you brute, you brute.
[Crow crying]
Leave my
fissionable material alone.
[Tom] God, a transparent
logie.
[Crow] Jack and Jill
went up the hill
to fetch a pail of heavy water.
[Mike] In an unrelated event,
[Tom] All my ex's died in Texas.
[Crow] Maybe they blew up
ZZ Top. Maybe.
[Tom] Whoop. Zip.
It were pretty how my wife
turned all purple. [chuckles]
[Crow] Sorry folks, it's all
nuclear behind here.
[Mike]
Are you happy, Mr. Teller?
-Drake and Smith. Security.
-[Tom] Excuse me.
Why aren't you folks drinking?
This is Texas.
Sorry, I got my orders.
No one enters this area.
Too much fallout for safety.
Alright officer.
Just a minute.
[Crow] Yeah I think a couple
of jumbo Slim Jims
will change your mind.
They're individually wrapped.
[Tom] And the
Bookmobile is there.
[Crow] The binoculars switched
to another viewpoint
They keep switching.
[Tom]
Here, these'll blow your mind.
[Mike]
It's a Frank Gehry building.
[Crow] Fine. If I can't get near
the fallout, I'll just smoke.
[Tom] Forget it, Jake.
It's Chinatown.
Be with
you in a minute Smitty.
[Mike] Gentle pressure.
See, did you notice the gentle
pressure?
Thank you. I learned.
Well, doctor,
you and your friends
have succeeded in blowing up
half the county.
[Crow] Yeah, oops.
There isn't enough left
out there to make ashes
I'm deeply sorry, of course.
-[Tom] Can I go now?
-But as I told you before,
I didn't do anything by choice.
[Crow] Yeah.
I warned Major Krenner of the
danger involved,
but you must realize,
his was a deranged mind.
[Crow] Mm-hmm.
All he could think of was the
creating of an invisible army.
And the power such a
force would give him.
-[Tom] Geez, I had to ask.
-You know, doctor,
this idea of an invisible army
is quite interesting.
[Crow] But I have to go.
Imagine what our
counterintelligence could
accomplish if they were able to
become invisible
whenever necessary.
The sector
intelligence agency
has already discussed
the possibilities...
[Tom] So don't try to
lord over me.
But my friend,
think of the danger
if the secret were
stolen from us.
It has happened before,
you know.
[Tom]
You big sack of Kraut gas.
What was that you were saying?
Perhaps it would be better if we
let the secret die with
Major Krenner and Joey Faust.
It's a serious problem.
What would you do?
[Mike]
What-- what was the question?
[Tom] Was that for us?
[Mike] What would we do?
I don't know.
[Crow] I didn't know there would
be a test.
[Mike] Something to think about,
though, hmm.
[doors closing]
Wow. What an interesting
dilemma.
Crow, what would you do?
-What would you do?
-Oh, that's easy.
If I were past mid-field,
I'd go for it.
Maybe just punt.
Oh, that's not what they mean.
Oh you...
-incorrigible little robot.
-[laughs]
No, the question is...
if you had a choice between
having your own invisible army
or blowing up a county in Texas,
which would it be?
Oh, Mike.
Come on, that's easy.
Under any circumstances,
blowing up a county in Texas
is justifiable.
[laughs]
-What-- what?
-Tom...
-What?
-My family's from Texas.
Oh, God. Oh, Mike.
No-- no, I had no idea.
I was just trying-- no--
Oh, God. Mike, I'm so sorry.
I'm kidding.
They're from Wisconsin.
I don't care what you
do to Texas.
I'm joking. Anyway...
We've got a letter to read.
Uh, it's actually
a transparent letter.
Put that up on still store
there, Cambot.
It's from Kathleen Donovan
and she writes, "Here's a little
invention for you."
And there's a nice little
picture there you can see.
Let's see. Yeah.
"Fill Tom Servo's head with
a creamy custardy yogurt
and you get... voila!
Soft-servo."
What do you know?
That's from Kathleen Donovan.
[Tom]
What happened to the letter?
-It's gone. It's transparent.
-[Tom] Oh, I see.
-[laughing]
-Thanks, Kathleen.
Mike, I have an invisible army,
you know.
They're right behind me.
No, no, no you don't.
My invisible army
is right behind me
and they just whomped
on your invisible army.
-Did not!
-Did too!
Crow T. Robot and Tom Servo...
what a couple of wacky,
mixed up bots.
-I'll see you later.
-Okay.
Hey. Look at you, you are a
skinny young man.
Here, have another
one of my rock hard,
flavorless butter cookies.
You know,
it's a wonderful dilemma.
Do I put an ice auger
through his chest
or do I enjoy another
delicious piece
of his wonderful
apple pandowdy?
Either way, I win!
[chuckles]
Well, Auntie McFrank,
it looks like you're over
your disappointment.
[clattering]
Squanto!
A Warriors Tale.
[slow theme music playing]
You see? I touch it,
it does it no harm.